KEVIN WADERA

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Senior **iOS** developer with years of experience in **Obj-C & Swift** development and including **SwiftUI**. Have also worked on **Android** development using **Java**. Additional, hands-on experience in JavaScript for cross-platform app development. Undergoing **AI/ML** courses in **python**.

WORK HISTORY

Software Developer Senior Specialist • Nasdaq Inc • 06/2020 - 10/2023

- Lead UI developer in a team of 8, working in an Agile environment, based out of Bangalore, India.
- Responsible for UI implementation in SwiftUI/Combine framework. Integrated 3rd party PDF reader into the app. Implemented document sync feature during the initial app launch phase in performance efficient background threads.
- Implemented data encoding and decoding features for secure storage. Included various business logic into the app.
- High profile customer base including board members of over 300 Fortune-500 companies across the world.

Member of Technical staff • Amadeus Software Labs • 11/2018 - 06/2020

- Responsible for managing and developing iOS Plugins for a Cordova based app using JavaScript.
- White label cross-platform app which gets customised for over 100 different Online Travel Agents (OTA's) in travel domain.
- Multiple awards winning app with customer base of over a million downloads.

EDUCATION

M. Eng. SOFTWARE ENG • 2023 - Dec 2024 • Concordia University, Montréal Undergoing master's to upskill myself. Undertaken new technologies including Bigdata, AI & Machine Learning.

B. Eng. Computer Science • 2006 - 2010 • VTU (Belgaum), India Majored in Computer Science with Algorithms, Computer Vision, and others.

PUBLICATION

 Recognition of machine printed broken characters based on gradient patterns and its spatial relationship - 2010 3rd IEEE ICCSIT, Chengdu, China

CONTACT

Address: Montréal, QC - H3V 1H4

Phone: (438) 779-8497

Email: kevin.wadera.ca@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Swift, Obj-C
- SwiftUI, Combine
- iOS
- Java
- Android
- Python
- Clean Swift, MVVM, VIPER
- Code Quality / Review
- Unit Testing / Debugging
- CI/CD integration
- API integration
- Agile development
- Team mentoring
- Cocoapods / Carthage

CERTIFICATIONS

 Certified Scrum Master (CSM) – Issued by Scrum Alliance, May 2018

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent)
- French (Intermediate)